### **Pulkit Goel**

Tech Lead | ML Infrastructure & Large-Scale Systems

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Tech Lead/Staff SWE, Search ML Infrastructure Google

📋 2023 - Present

- Mountain View, CA
- Set team direction (OKRs, prioritization) and spearheaded the architecture of a production-scale LLM inference framework, adopted by 150 client teams and supporting over 2500 QPS across diverse models.
- Enabled the launch of critical features like AI Overviews by increasing offline TPU duty cycle to >70%—a crucial launch requirement that saved O(10k)s chips—through novel traffic optimization and hardware fungibility.
- Championed a few proposals for Google-wide infrastructure optimizations that were successfully launched, partnering with Flume & LLM Deployment teams to define OKRs and steer progress.
- Provided dedicated technical support and subject matter expertise to a client base of over 200 engineers, ensuring successful platform adoption and resolving complex issues.

## Senior Software Engineer, Search Infrastructure Google

**1** 2020 - 2023

- Mountain View, CA
- Co-designed and drove development of APIMirror, a service enabling products like Gemini Extensions to securely interact with third-party APIs.
- Led a team to build 3PDB, a scalable C++ platform ingesting 30 terabytes of structured data daily from thousands of third-party providers, now a Google-wide standard.

# Software Engineer, Data Ingestion Infrastructure Google

**2015 - 2020** 

- Mountain View, CA
- Built and scaled numerous large-scale C++ distributed systems, including the first backend for the public Google Indexing API and the serving infrastructure for Google News.

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- P. Goel, "Load balancing on the cloud," M.S. thesis, International Institute of Information Technology, Hyderabad, 2017.
- P. Goel, K. Rishabh, and V. Varma, "An alternate load distribution scheme in dhts," in 2017 IEEE International Conference on Cloud Computing Technology and Science (CloudCom), IEEE, 2017, pp. 218–222.
- P. Goel, L. Srinivasan, and V. Varma, "An adaptive routing scheme for heterogeneous data-flows using openflow," in 2015 IEEE International Conference on Cloud Computing in Emerging Markets (CCEM), IEEE, 2015, pp. 52–58.



#### **ABOUT ME**

"A Staff Engineer combining a decade of systems expertise with a long-standing passion for machine learning. Two years ago, I formally pivoted into a challenging ML infrastructure role, successfully applying years of self-directed learning on ML models and deployment bottlenecks. My goal is to tackle core ML challenges by building highly efficient, next-generation platforms."

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

ML & Data Infrastructure

Large-Scale Distributed Systems

ML Workload Optimization

LLM Inference & Serving

API Design

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### JeopardyGPT 69

Built a complex, multiplayer web game using LLMs.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech (Hons) & MS by Research, CS International Institute of Information Technology (IIIT)

**2010 - 2015** 

Hyderabad, India

### **HONORS & AWARDS**



ACM-ICPC World Finalist § 2014 & 2015



23 Peer Bonuses

Received last year for impact and collaboration on ML infrastructure.

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

# Software Engineer Intern Facebook

**1** 2014

Menlo Park, CA

## Software Engineer Intern Directi

□ 2013

Mumbai, India